Preet Patel

GitHub | In LinkedIn | ⊕ Website | ■ pbpa@ucdavis.edu | -16307156148

SUMMARY

I am a **third year Astrophysics graduate student** pursuing a PhD at the University of California - Davis (UCD). My research areas include: galaxy formation, stellar elemental abundances, computational astrophysics, simulations, & high-performance computing, big data, and statistical methods.

EDUCATION

In Progress PhD in Physics & Astronomy at University of California - Davis

2015 - 2019 B.S. in Astrophysics at University of Michigan - Ann Arbor

Minor in Statistics

2015 - 2019 B.S. in Physics at University of Michigan - Ann Arbor

Publications

Patel, Preet B. et al. (June 2022). "Predictions for complex distributions of stellar elemental abundances in low-mass galaxies". In: 512.4, pp. 5671–5685. DOI: 10.1093/mnras/stac834. arXiv: 2110.08287 [astro-ph.GA].

Presentations

Talk: Galaxy Evolution Conference at CalTech

Aug 2022

 15 minute talk at the GalFRESCA conference held in Pasadena, CA. Detailing my published research from the last two years.

AAS Poster: Predictions for Complex Elemental Abundance Patterns in Low Mass Galaxies Jan 2020

- Preet Patel, Sarah Loebman, Andrew Wetzel; FIRE Collaboration
- Bibcode: 2020AAS...23516827P

Guest Lecture: COSMOS Summer Program at UC Davis

July 2019

- Invited to speak in a joint lecture about GAIA, the Milky Way, and the Local Group at UC Davis.
- Sarah Loebman, Preet Patel

EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant (TA)

Multiple - Now

- Dates of TA: Jan 2023 Now; March 2022 June 2023; Oct 2020 June 2021
- Classes: PHY 9B (F2020), PHY 7A (W2021), AST 25 (SPR2021), AST 25 (SPR2022), PHY 10 (now).

Grad Student Researcher (GSR)

Multiple - Jan 2023

- Dates of GSR: June 2022 Dec 2022; June 2021 March 2022
- Graduate student research with Professor Andrew Wetzel in the Wetzelgroup. Characterize simulations of low-mass galaxies and develop modules for testing models of stellar feedback in post-processing.

Undergraduate Student Researcher (UC Davis)

June 2019 - Aug 2019

Bluewaters Student Intern

May 2018 - May 2019

One of 19 students selected to be in the final cadre of the BlueWaters Student Internship program. 2 weeks of training at the Petascale Institute and a year of research with Prof. Sarah Loebman.

SKILLS

Academic Scientific Writing, Persurasive Writing, Calculus, Linear Algebra, Statistical Methods, some

Differential Geometry

Technical Version Control, proficiency in Python, R, C/CUDA, HTML, Dreamweaver, Data visualization, Data Animation

Language English, Gujarati, & working proficiency in Spanish

Other Graphic Design (Photoshop, Činema 4D), Media Production (Sony Vegas, After Effects)